[
  {
    "questionText": "Henüz ____ arabası gelmemiş.",
    "answer": "çöp",
    "hint": "The garbage truck hasn't arrived yet."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "____ bir kız kardeşi vardı.",
    "answer": "Evli",
    "hint": "He had a married sister."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Sırtını tümüyle açıkta bırakan ____ elbise giymişti.",
    "answer": "bir",
    "hint": "She was wearing a dress with the back completely bare."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Etnik ____ diye bir şey yok orada.",
    "answer": "ayrılık",
    "hint": "There is no such ethnic discrimination there."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Çocuklar ____ çıplak ayak futbol oynarlarmış.",
    "answer": "mahallede",
    "hint": "The kids used to play football in their bare feet in that neighborhood."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Mektupların kenarı çiçeklerle ____.",
    "answer": "süslenmişti",
    "hint": "The margins of the letters were decorated with flowers."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Rock gruplarını dinlerken, kafamda ____ bir yapı şekillendi.",
    "answer": "müzikal",
    "hint": "While I was listening to the rock bands, a musical composition was forming in my mind."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Adam yorgun, hasta, ____.",
    "answer": "tükenmiş",
    "hint": "The man is tired, ill and exhausted."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Sözlük ____ tiplerine ayrıntılı arama, hızlı arama gibi seçenekler eklemiş.",
    "answer": "arama",
    "hint": "Options like detailed search and quick search are being added to online dictionaries."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Kadın ____ içinde bakıyordu.",
    "answer": "şaşkınlık",
    "hint": "The woman was looking at everyone in confusion."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Ev sahibi ____ çok kaba adam.",
    "answer": "de",
    "hint": "His landlord is also a rude man."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "İşlendiğinde ____ olmayan bir fiil daha sonra suç olabilir.",
    "answer": "suç",
    "hint": "An act can be considered a crime, even if it wasn't at the time of execution."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Sevmekten yoksun ____ akıl, dengesizliklere yol açıyor.",
    "answer": "bir",
    "hint": "A mind deprived of love can become unbalanced."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Son yıllarda maddi ____ acılar yaşadınız.",
    "answer": "manevi",
    "hint": "You've experienced both physical and emotional pain in recent years."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Belli belirsiz bir hüzün duygusu ____ içimde.",
    "answer": "var",
    "hint": "I feel an undefined melancholy deep in my soul."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Eve gelirken aldığı taze ____ ikindi kahvaltısı yaparlardı.",
    "answer": "ekmekle",
    "hint": "They used to have brunch with the fresh bread he bought on his way back home."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Okul öncesinde prensip olarak çocuk, ____ ve disiplini öğrenmeli.",
    "answer": "temizlik",
    "hint": "During preschool, in principle a child should learn personal hygiene and self-discipline."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Erkek aslan ____ yarısını yiyor.",
    "answer": "avın",
    "hint": "The male lion eats half of the hunt."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Son onbeş ____ birçok da makale yazdım.",
    "answer": "yılda",
    "hint": "I've also written lots of articles in the last 15 years."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "____ bütün subayları ya şehit ya yaralıdır.",
    "answer": "Alayın",
    "hint": "All the officers in the regiment were either martyrs or wounded."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Kimi ____ ışıksızdır.",
    "answer": "liman",
    "hint": "Some ports are unlit."
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Sanatçı ____ gibi varolmalıdır.",
    "answer": "yokmuş",
    "hint": "An artist should exist as if she were invisible."
  }
]